[
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct extension of the user-defined header file in C++.",
        "answer": ".h extensions is the extension used for user-defined header files.",
        "options": [
            ".cpp",
            ".hg",
            ".h",
            ".hf"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the incorrect constructor type.",
        "answer": "Friend constructor is not a type of constructor.",
        "options": [
            "Friend constructor",
            "Default constructor",
            "Parameterized constructor",
            "Copy constructor"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "C++ uses which approach?",
        "answer": "C++ is an object oriented language and it uses bottom-up approach.",
        "options": [
            "right -left",
            "Top-down",
            "left-right",
            "bottom -up"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following data type is supported in C++ but not in C?",
        "answer": "boolean data type is not supported in C.",
        "options": [
            "int",
            "bool",
            "double",
            "float"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct syntax for declaring arrays in C++.",
        "answer": "int arr[10] is the correct syntax for declaring arrays.",
        "options": [
            "array arr[10]",
            "array{10}",
            "int arr[10]",
            "int arr"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Size of wchat_t is.",
        "answer": "Size of wchat_t depends on the number of bits in the system as the compiler wants to make the CPU as efficient as possible in accessing the next  value.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "4",
            "2 or 4",
            "Depends on number of bits in system"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is “address of operator”?.",
        "answer": "& is used to denote the address of operator.",
        "options": [
            "*",
            "&",
            "[]",
            "&&"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct example for a pre-increment operator.",
        "answer": "++n is a pre-increment operator.",
        "options": [
            "++n",
            "n++",
            "- -n",
            "+n"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following loops is best when we know the number of iterations?",
        "answer": "When the number of iterations are known, for loop is best to use.",
        "options": [
            "While loop",
            "Do while",
            "For loop",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the scope resolution operator.",
        "answer": ":: is the scope resolution operator.",
        "options": [
            ":",
            "::",
            "?",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "goto can be classified into?",
        "answer": "goto can be classified into a label.",
        "options": [
            "label",
            "variable",
            "operator",
            "function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct definition of ‘*’ operator in pointer.",
        "answer": "* denotes the value of the address operator.",
        "options": [
            "Address of operator",
            "Value of address operator",
            "Multiplication operator",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "By which of the following can the if-else statement be replaced?",
        "answer": "if-else statement can be replaced by conditional operator.",
        "options": [
            "Bitwise operator",
            "Logical operator",
            "Conditional operator",
            "Arithmetic operator"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct default return value of function.",
        "answer": "The default return value of function is int.",
        "options": [
            "int",
            "void",
            "char",
            "float"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Using which of the following data type can 19.54 be represented?",
        "answer": "19.54 can be represented using double.",
        "options": [
            "void",
            "double",
            "int",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "When can an inline function be expanded?",
        "answer": "Inline functions are expanded during compile time.",
        "options": [
            "Runtime",
            "Compile time",
            "Never gets expanded",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct function from which the execution of C++ program starts?",
        "answer": "Execution of C++ always starts from main().",
        "options": [
            "new()",
            "start()",
            "pow()",
            "main()"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct option which is mandatory in a function.",
        "answer": "While writing a function,both return type and function name are mandatory.",
        "options": [
            "return_type",
            "parameters",
            "function_name",
            "Both a and c"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "The constants in C++ are also known as?",
        "answer": "The constants in C++ are also known as literals.",
        "options": [
            "pre-processor",
            "literals",
            "const",
            "none"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Using which of the following keywords can an exception be generated?",
        "answer": "Using the throw keyword, an exception can be generated in C++.",
        "options": [
            "threw",
            "throws",
            "throw",
            "catch"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the size of int datatype in C++.",
        "answer": "The size of int datatype depends on compiler to compiler.",
        "options": [
            "1 byte",
            "2 bytes",
            "4 bytes",
            "Depends on compiler"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following types is the language C++?",
        "answer": "C++ is a statically typed language.",
        "options": [
            "Procedural",
            "Statically typed language",
            "Dynamically typed language",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the ASCII value of ‘\\0’ character?",
        "answer": "Value of ‘\\0’ is 0.",
        "options": [
            "32",
            "24",
            "48",
            "0"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the format string among the following.",
        "answer": "%d is known as the format string.",
        "options": [
            "&",
            "\\n",
            "%d",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is do-while loop also known as?",
        "answer": "do-while loop also known as exit control loop.",
        "options": [
            "Exit control",
            "Entry control",
            "Per tested",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct range of signed char.",
        "answer": "The range of signed char is -128 to 127.",
        "options": [
            "-256 to 255",
            "-128 to 127",
            "0 to 255",
            "0 to 127"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the size of the below struct.Struct{\nInt a;\nChar b;\nFloat c;\n}",
        "answer": "Size of int = 2 byte, char = 1 byte and float = 4 bytes. Therefore total size = 2 + 1 + 4 = 7 bytes.",
        "options": [
            "2",
            "4",
            "7",
            "10"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the logical AND operator.",
        "answer": "&& is known as the AND operator.",
        "options": [
            "||",
            "&&",
            "&",
            "!"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the correct subscript operator.",
        "answer": "[ ] is known as the subscript operator.",
        "options": [
            "[ ]",
            "{ }",
            "*",
            "( )"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the type of loop which is guaranteed to execute at-least once?",
        "answer": "do-while loop is.guaranteed to execute at-least once.",
        "options": [
            "for loop",
            "do-while",
            "while",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How much bytes of memory does void occupy?",
        "answer": "void does not occupy any memory. Hence, it takes 0 bytes of memory.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "0",
            "2",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Why are comments used?",
        "answer": "Comments are used to help others read & understand the program.",
        "options": [
            "Make the program run faster",
            "To help others read & understand the program",
            "Increase the size of the executable program",
            "Make a program compile easier"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total types of errors in C++.",
        "answer": "There are three types of errors in C++- syntax errors, runtime errors, logic errors.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the storage classes that have global visibility.",
        "answer": "extern is the storage classes that have global visibility.",
        "options": [
            "extern",
            "auto",
            "register",
            "static"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Choose the option below which is not a member of class.",
        "answer": "Friend function is not a member of class.",
        "options": [
            "Friend function",
            "Static function",
            "Virtual function",
            "Const function"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Total types of constructors in C++ are?",
        "answer": "There are three types of constructors in C++ - .default constructor, parameterized constructor and copy constructor.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the number of parameters that a default constructor requires?",
        "answer": "Default constructor does not require any parameter.",
        "options": [
            "0",
            "1",
            "2",
            "3"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What does a C++ class hold?",
        "answer": "C++ class holds both Function and data.",
        "options": [
            "Function",
            "Data",
            "Arrays",
            "Both a and b"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Data members and member functions of a class are private by.default. True or False?",
        "answer": "True. Data members and member functions of a class are always private by default.",
        "options": [
            "True",
            "False",
            "Depends on code",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which pillar of OOPS does base class and derived class relationship come?",
        "answer": "Base class and derived class relationship comes under inheritance.",
        "options": [
            "Polymorphism",
            "Inheritance",
            "Encapsulation",
            "Abstraction"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following functions can be inherited from base class?",
        "answer": "None of the functions can be inherited from the base class.",
        "options": [
            "Constructor",
            "Destructor",
            "Static",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the output of the following program.main(){\n  Float a = 5;\n  switch(a){\n     Case 5: cout <<”Interviewbit”;\n     Default: cout <<”Scaler”;\n  }\n}",
        "answer": "The following code will give error as we can pass either integer or character data type in switch.",
        "options": [
            "Interviewbit",
            "Scaler",
            "InterviewbitScaler",
            "Error"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the output of the following program.main(){\n  int a = 10, b, c;\n  b  = a++;\n  c = a;\n  cout << a << “ “ <<b <<” “<< c << endl;\n}",
        "answer": "The initial value of a is 10. Now, after post incrementing, the value of a is 11, and the previous value of a is assigned to b. Hence b = 10. c is assigned the updated value. Hence, the answer is 11 10 11.",
        "options": [
            "10 11 11",
            "11 11 11",
            "11 10 11",
            "10 10 10"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the output of the following program.main(){\n  int a, b = 10;\n  a = 95 / 10;\n  cout << a << endl;\n}",
        "answer": "Since integer division is performed, 9 is the answer.",
        "options": [
            "9",
            "9.5",
            "10",
            "9.0"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times will the print statement be executed?main(){\n  int i = 0;\n  label:\n  cout << “Interviewbit;\n  i++;\n  if(i < 3){\n    goto label;\n  }\n}",
        "answer": "Interviewbit will be printed 3 times, since for every if i < 3, it goes to label and an iteration occurs.",
        "options": [
            "1 time",
            "2 times",
            "3 times",
            "Error"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the output of the following program.main(){\n cout <<  -10 - 10 -10;\n}",
        "answer": "Since this is an arithmetic operation, -30 is the correct answer.",
        "options": [
            "0",
            "-30",
            "30",
            "20"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the output of the following program.main(){\n int a = 10 / 0;\n}",
        "answer": "Dividing integer by 0 gives arithmetic exception, since it is undefined.",
        "options": [
            "0",
            "Compilation error",
            "exception",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the correct escape sequence used for the new line.",
        "answer": "\\n is the escape sequence used for the new line.",
        "options": [
            "\\t",
            "\\n",
            "\\a",
            "None"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the output of the following program.main(){\n char ch[] = “Interviewbit Scaler”; \n int l = strlen(ch);\n cout << l << endl;\n}",
        "answer": "The length of the string “Interviewbit” is 12 and that of “Scaler” is 6. Since, there is a space in between, an additional 1 needs to be counted.Hence, output = 12 +  6 + 1 = 19.",
        "options": [
            "18",
            "19",
            "20",
            "21"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Find the output of the following program.main(){\n int i = (1, 2, 3);\n cout << i << endl;\n}",
        "answer": "The last value is given precedence. Hence, the output is 3.",
        "options": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "Error"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct identifier?",
        "answer": "var_name12 is the correct identifier as in identifiers, it can contain lowercase/uppercase letters or digits. It should start with non digits and also should not contain any special characters.",
        "options": [
            "2var_name",
            "2VAR_NAME",
            "$varname",
            "var_name12"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a type of inheritance?",
        "answer": "Distributed  is not a type of inheritance.",
        "options": [
            "Multiple",
            "Multilevel",
            "Distributed",
            "Heirarchical"
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an object in c++?",
        "answer": "An object is an instance of class.",
        "options": [
            "It is function of class",
            "It is instance of class",
            "It is datatype of class",
            "It is part of the syntax of class"
        ]
    }
]